Scientists Collection 1563-1973 Mss.509.L56
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1563-1973; 5.0 lin. feet 10 upright boxes, 8 oversize folders.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1826 May 29; Zach, Franz Xaver, Freiherr von, 1754-1832
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1826 Jun. 6; Raglan, Fitzroy James Henry Somerset, 1st Baron
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1826 Aug. 13; Exeter, Marquis of
  - Letter to Brame, B., 1826 Dec. 14; Clarkson, Thomas
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1827 Mar. 1; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1827 May 29; Sinclair, John
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1827 Jul. 9; Suffield, Edward Harbord, 3rd Baron
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1827 Jul. 15; Harcourt, Edward, Archbishop of York
  - Letter to Torrey, John, 1796-1873, 1827 Sep. 11; Pitcher, Zina, 1797-1872
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1827 Sep. 26; Russell, John, 6th Duke of Bedford
  - Letter to la Roche, Monsieur, 1827 Dec. 12; Valentin, Louis, 1758-1829
  - Letter to Gwatkin, Thomas, 1828 Apr. 4; Babington, William, 1756-1833
  - Letter to Bertrand, Arthur, 1828 Apr. 30; Zach, Franz Xaver, Freiherr von, 1754-1832
  - Letter to Cleaveland, Parker, 1828 May 13; Hitchcock, Edward, 1793-1864
    1972-817ms
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1828 Jun. 29; Brunel, Isambard Kingdom, 1806-1859
  - Letter to la Roche, Monsieur, 1828 Oct. 6; Valentin, Louis, 1758-1829
  - Letter to Haines, Reuben, 1828 Nov. 18; Godman, John D., (John Davidson), 1794-1830
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1828 Dec. 20; Lyttelton, William Henry Lyttelton, 3rd Baron
  - Letter to la Roche, Monsieur, 1829 Jan. 25; Valentin, Louis, 1758-1829
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1829 Mar. 14; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867
  - Letter to Green, Jacob, 1790-1841, 1829 Jun.; Swainson
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1829 Jul. 28; Russell, John, 6th Duke of Bedford
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1829 Sep. 21; Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868
  - Letter to Carey & Lea, 1829 Dec. 9; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1829 Dec. 21; Raglan, Fitzroy James Henry Somerset, 1st Baron
  - Letter to Carey, Mathew, 1760-1839, 1830 Jan. 26; Priestley, Joseph Rayner
  - Letter to Stemann, von, 1830 Feb. 24; Pedersen, P.
  - Letter to Lewis, L., 1830 Nov.; Stuart, C. C.
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1831 Mar. 25; Rennie, John
  - Letter to Featherstonhaugh, George William, 1780-1866, 1831 Jul. 10; Cooper, Thomas, 1805-1892
  - Letter to Pompée, 1831 Jul. 31; Mathieu
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1831 Aug. 6; Taylor, Richard C., (Richard Cowling), 1789-1851
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1831 Nov. 6; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1831 Dec. 22; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1832 Jan. 1; Manners, John Henry, Duke of Rutland, 1778-1857
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1832 Jan. 2; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
    Photocopy of original in the College of Physicians. Unlocated June 2011.
  - Letter to Stark, John, 1832 Jan. 3; Robinson, John
  - Letter to Vulliamy & Sons, 1832 Jan. 20; Ossory and Kilkenny, Bishop of
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1832 Feb. 24; Johnston, Jas. F. W., (James Finlay Weir), 1796-1855
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1832 Mar. 6; Frederick, Augustus, Duke of Sussex
  - Letter to Ingham, Samuel Delucenna, 1779-1860, 1832 Jun. 8; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    1962-32ms
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1832 Oct. 2; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
  - Letter to Franks, F., 1832 Dec. 3; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
  - Letter to Murchison, Roderick Impey, 1792-1871, 1832; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
    1962-2274ms
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1833 Jan. 3; Amherst of Arracan, William Pitt Amherst
  - Letter to Children, J. M., 1833 Feb. 7; Gilbert, Davies, 1767-1839
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1833 Feb. 28; Pland, J.
  - Letter to Vulliamy & Sons, 1833 May 24; Canterbury, Charles Manners-Sutton, 1st Viscount
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1833 Sep. 5; Orr, William
    1977-1301ms
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1833 Oct. 29; Wilson, Daniel, Bishop of Calcutta
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1833 Dec. 28; Howley, William, 1766-1848
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1834 Jan. 20; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1834 Feb. 23; Leveson-Gover, George Granville, Duke of Sutherland
  - Letter to Parsons, Usher, 1834 Sep. 3; Hays, Isaac,1796-1879.
  - Letter to Carfield, William, 1834 Dec. 2; Keate, Robert, 1777-1857
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1835 Mar. 6; Greville, Robert Kaye, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867, 1835 Apr. 15; Atkin, Arthur
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1835 Apr. 18; Wied, Maximilian Prinz von
  - Letter to Lubbock, Richard, 1835 Jun. 15; Yarrell, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1835 Jun. 24; MacCulloch, John Ramsay
  - Letter to Geoffroy Saint-Hillaire, Étienne, 1772-1844, 1835 Jul. 7; Gaimard, Paul, 1790-1858
  - Letter to Dickerson, Mahlon, 1770-1853, 1835 Jul. 13; Day, Jeremiah, 1773-1867
    Recommending Sam Gallin (?) for an appointment as schoolmaster in the U.S. Navy.
    Dickerson, Mahlon, 1770-1853
  - Letter to Civiale, Docteur Jean, 1792-1867, 1835 Aug. 2; Berzelius, Jons Jakob, Friherre, 1779-1848
  - Letter to Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875, 1835 Sep. 17; Greville, Robert Kaye, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1835 Dec. 13; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1836 Jan. 7; Daniell, John Frederic, 1790-1845
  - Letter to Townsend, John Kirk, 1809-1851, 1836 Mar. 3; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1836 Mar. 21; Daniell, John Frederic, 1790-1845
  - Letter to Back, T. R., 1836 Mar. 26; Cooper, William
  - Letter to Brayley, 1836 Apr. 9; Lardner, Dionysius, 1793-1859
  - Letter to Hughes, William, 1836 May 19; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Rigaud, Stephen Peter, 1774-1839, 1836 Aug. 18; Unidentified
  - Letter to Aspinwall, Thomas, 1786-1876, 1836 Aug. 19; Parkman, George, 1790-1849
  - Letter to Buchanan, R., 1836 Aug. 29; Troost, Gerard, 1776-1850
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1836 Nov. 14; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1837 Jan. 24; Jardine, William, Sir, 1800-1874
  - Letter to Torrey, John, 1796-1873, 1837 May 17; Hall, James
  - Letter to Beck, Theodric Romeyn, 1791-1855, 1837 May 22; De Kay, James E., (James Ellsworth), 1792-1851
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1837 Jul. 6; Ely, Bishop of
  - Letter to Stark, John, 1837 Sep. 25; Neill, Patrick, 1796-1851
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1837 Oct. 20; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
  - Letter to Bloodgood, De Witt, 1837 Nov. 4; McMurtrie, H.
  - Letter to Ridgely, Charles, 1838 Feb. 10; Eights, James, 1798-1882
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1838 Feb. 17; Fienne, Henry Pelham, 4th duke of Newcastle
  - Letter to Cooper, Astley, 1768-1841, 1838 Mar. 15; Weeding, Thomas
    Contains reply of Cooper to Weeding
  - Letter to Torrey, John, 1796-1873, 1838 Apr. 16; Perrine, H.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1838 Jun. 29; Gilbert, Davies, 1767-1839
  - Letter to Geoffroy Saint-Hillaire, Étienne, 1772-1844, 1838 Jul. 29; Du Mortier, B. C., (Barthelmey Charles), 1797-1878
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1838 Aug. 3; Johnston, George, 1797-1855
  - Letter to Linacre, Mr., 1838 Aug. 16; Rigaud, Stephen Peter, 1774-1839
  - Letter to Royal Society of London, 1838 Aug. 19; Frederick, Augustus, Duke of Sussex
  - Sketch: "Captn. Back on Gt. Slave Lake.", 1838 Aug.; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
    A. D. Bache, rather than "Back"?
  - Sketch: "President of Brith. Asso.n", 1838 Aug.; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Black, Adam, 1838 Oct. 20; Phillips, John, 1800-1874
  - Letter to Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844, 1838 Oct. 26; Prichard, H.
  - Letter to Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875, 1838 Nov. 7; Sykes, W. H.
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1838 Nov. 20; Willoughby, Henry Peyto Verney, Baron
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1838 Dec. 16; Kidd, William
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1839 Jan. 1; Arden, Charles George Perceval, Baron
  - Letter to Lunn, J., 1839 Apr. 3; Yarrell, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1839 Jul. 24; Wied, Maximilian Prinz von
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1839 Sep. 14; Bournall, J.E.
  - Letter to Yates, James, 1839 Oct. 16; Prichard, James Cowles, 1786-1848
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1839 Nov. 15; Cartwright, J.
  - Letter to Atlee, John L., 1839 Dec. 28; Hays, Isaac,1796-1879.
  - Letter to Tywell, F., 1839; Cooper, Astley, Sir, 1768-1841
    Includes a portrait of Cooper, published by H. Renshaw.
  - Letter to Charles, 1840 Jan. 18; Forbes, James D.
  - Letter to Archibald, C. D., 1840 Apr. 19; Stanley, Edward Smith, 13th Earl of Derby, 1775-1851
  - Letter to Cohen, J. J., 1840 Apr. 20; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1840 Apr. 20; Fitzclarence, Lord Adolphus
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1840 May 21; Midleton, Lord
  - Letter to Genty de Bussy, Pierre. 1793-1867, 1840 Jun. 5; Héricart-Ferrand,, Louis Étienne François, vicomte de Thury, 1776-1854
  - Letter to Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875, 1840 Jul. 24; Doubleday, Edward
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1840 Aug. 10; Brown, Robert
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, 1840 Aug. 17; Spencer, George, 5th Duke of Marlborough
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1840 Sep. 22; Ansted, D. T. (David Thomas), 1814-1880
  - Letter to Hays, Isaac, 1796-1879, 1840 Oct. 9; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to Soutwell, H. P., 1840 Oct. 26; Boott, Francis
  - Letter to Stark, John, 1841 Jan. 18; Johnston, Jas. F. W., (James Finlay Weir), 1796-1855
  - Letter to Boyd, J. B., 1841 Mar. 3; Kirtland, J. P., (Jared Potter), 1793-1877
  - Letter to Geoffroy Saint-Hillaire, Étienne, 1772-1844, 1841 Mar. 17; Matteucci, Carlo, 1811-1868
  - Letter to Geoffroy Saint-Hillaire, Étienne, 1772-1844, 1841 Apr. 9; Elie de Beaumont, L., (Leonce), 1798-1874
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1841 Apr. 10; Lyell, Charles, Sir, 1797-1875
  - Letter to Ilington Scientific Institution, 1841 May 7; Ansted, D. T. (David Thomas), 1814-1880
  - Letter to Brown, F., 1841 Jul. 20; Kane, Robert
  - Letter to Washington, W. C., 1841 Jul. 30; Brodie, Benjamin, Sir, 1783-1862
  - Autograph, 1841 Dec. 22; Newman, Edward
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1842 Jan. 24; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
  - Letter to Ingham, Samuel Delucenna, 1779-1860, 1842 Apr. 19; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
  - Letter to Ingham, Samuel Delucenna, 1779-1860, 1842 Apr. 20; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
  - Upon chronometrical operations, 1842 Apr.; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
  - Letter to Anderson, Col., 1842 May 31; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter to Townsend, John Kirk, 1809-1851, 1842 Jun. 12; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1842 Jul. 19; Sowerby,, G. B., (George Brettingham), 1812-1884
  - Letter to Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843, 1842 Jul. 23; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
  - Letter to Van Voorst, Mr., 1842 Aug. 18; Lowe, Richard Thomas
  - Letter to Gilbert., 1842 Oct. 3; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
  - Letter to Bewlay, Thomas, 1842 Oct. 12; Phipps, Mulgrave, Earl of
  - Letter to Bowerbank, J. Scott, 1842 Nov. 19; Smith, John Pye, 1774-1851
  - Phrenological reading, 1843 Mar. 10; Deville, James
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1843 Mar. 23; Playfair, Lyon Playfair, Baron, 1818-1898
  - Letter to Elton, Romeo, 1790-1870, 1843 May 2; Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873
  - Letter to Clark, Eleanora, 1843 Jun. 24; Clark, Thomas
  - Subscription for Audubon's Quadrupeds., 1843 Jul. 22; Burlington, Lord
  - Letter to Phillips, My dear, 1843 Sep. 8; De La Beche, Henry T., (Henry Thomas), 1796-1855
  - Letter to Heroast, Miss, 1843 Nov. 27; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Coleridge, Edward, 1844 Jan. 12; Hawkins, Edward
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1844 Mar. 30; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
  - Letter to De la Beche, Henry T. (Henry Thomas), 1796-1855, 1844 Jul. 3; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Margueritte, 1844 Aug. 24; Pelouze, Théophile Jules, 1807-1867
  - Letter to Shaw, Mr., 1844 Sep. 1; Waterton, Charles, 1782-1865
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1844 Nov. 6; Children, John George
  - Letter to Brockden, W. (?), 1844 Dec. 30; Brande, William T.
  - Letter to Twining, Alexander Catlin, 1845 Feb. 10; Maury, Matthew Fontaine, 1806-1873
    1983-1444ms
  - Letter to Wilkes, Charles, 1845 Mar. 28; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to Croker, John Wilson, 1780-1857, 1845 Apr. 15; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1845 Jul. 3; Children, John George
  - Subscribers to his telescope, 1845 Jul.; Miller, L. A.
    1977-2081ms
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1845 Nov. 1; Phillips, John, 1800-1874
  - Letter to Girard, 1845 Nov. 8; Garruly,
  - Letter to [George Peacock], 1846 Mar. 26; Sabine, Edward, Sir, 1788-1883
  - Letter to Shaw, Mrs., 1846 Apr. 2; Rogers, Samuel.
  - Letter to Syme, John, 1846 May 21; Wilson, James
  - Letter to Briggs, George Nixon, 1846 Jul. 29; Hitchcock, Edward, 1793-1864
  - Letter to Miller, 1846 Aug. 13; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Randall, Mr., 1846 Aug. 25; Hall, James
  - Letter to Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867, 1846 Oct. 2; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867
  - Letter to Gardiners Chronicle. Editor, 1846 Nov. 19; Whitby, M. A. T., ?
    Silkworms
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1847 Feb. 6; Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861
    1974-994h.ms
  - Letter to Syme, John, 1847 Mar. 18; Neill, Patrick, 1796-1851
  - Letter to Seaton, W., 1847 Apr. 6; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Letter to Dickens, Miss, 1847 Oct. 26; Raglan, Fitzroy James Henry Somerset, 1st Baron
  - Letter to Fillmore, P. M., 1847 Nov. 4; Davies, Charles
  - Letter to Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896, 1847 Nov. 18; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to Ponfick, Dr., 1848 Jan. 15; Marschner, Heinrich, 1795-1861
  - Letter to Clark, George, 1848 Jun. 12; Wilson, James
  - Letter to Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867, 1848 Jun. 15; Nichol, John Pringle, 1804-1859
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1848 Jun. 24; Pollock, Frederick
  - Letter to Corning, Mr., 1848 Jul. 3; Hall, James
  - Letter to Stewart, F. A., 1848 Jul.; Mott, Valentine, 1785-1865
  - Letter to Carpenter, William, 1797-1874, 1848 Aug. 8; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Cupples, Mr., 1848 Aug. 13; Brown, Samuel
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1848 Aug. 18; Sidney, Edwin
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1848 Sep. 4; Children, John George
  - Letter to Wilkes, Charles, 1798-1877, 1848 Sep. 27; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
  - Letter to Cormic, Dr., 1848 Oct. 25; Photocopy.; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    College of Physicians of Philadelphia
  - Letter to Hunt, Robert, 1848 Nov. 16; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1849 Feb. 15; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1849 Feb. 19; Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868
  - Letter to Syme, John, 1849 Mar. 7; Neill, Patrick, 1796-1851
  - Letter to Syme, John, 1849 Mar. 10; Neill, Patrick, 1796-1851
  - Letter to Syme, John, 1849 Mar. 28; Neill, Patrick, 1796-1851
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1849 May 3; Allman, George James
  - Letter to Charles, Sir, 1849 May 9; Couch, Richard Quiller
  - Letter to Gray, A[sa], 1849 Sept. 11; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    1965 2464ms
  - Letter to Clibborn, Edward, 1849 Oct. 27; Worsaae, Jens Jakob Asmussen, 1821-1885
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1849 Nov. 26; Jardine, William, Sir, 1800-1874
  - Letter to Fenwick, Miss, 1850 Jan. 15; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861s, 1850 Jun. 18, 28; Sabine, Edward, Sir, 1788-1883
  - Letter to Nasmyth, James, 1808-1890, 1850 Aug. 30; Lassell, William, 1799-1880
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1850 Oct. 7; Buckland, W. H.
  - Letter to Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867, 1850 Oct. 17; Nichol, John Pringle, 1804-1859
  - Letter to Rogers, Reginald, 1850 Nov. 11; Southey, Henry Herbert, 1783-1865
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1850 Dec. 7; Saunders, W. Wilson, (William Wilson), 1809-1879
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1850 Dec. 16; Fairbairn, William, Sir, 1789-1874
  - Letter to Murray, John, 1808-1892, 1851 Jan. 2; Yarrell, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1851 Jun. 6; Phillips, John, 1800-1874
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1851 Jun. 28; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
  - Letter to Ransome, George, 1851 Jun. 30; Woodward, Samuel Peckworth, 1821-1865
  - Letter to Potter, Henry, 1851 Oct. 2; Potter, Richard
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1851 Nov. 5; Swan, William
  - Letter to Cooke, Robert, 1851 Nov. 24; Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1852 Jan. 7; De La Beche, Henry T., (Henry Thomas), 1796-1855
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1852 Jan. 19; Curtis, John
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1852 Feb. 18; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to Stewart, F. A., 1852 Mar. 18; Mott, Valentine, 1785-1865
  - Letter to Gray, Mrs., 1852 May 13; Greville, Robert Kaye, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Grove, G., 1852 May 18; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
  - Autograph, 1852 Jul. 3; Waterton, Charles, 1782-1865
  - Letter to Ispwich Museum. Secretaries, 1852 Aug. 7; Ross, James Clark
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1852 Aug. 9; Westwood, J. O. (John Obadiah), 1805-1893
  - Letter to Owen, Richard, 1804-1892, 1852 Aug. 16; Pettigrew, W.
  - Letter to Coster, Mrs., 1852 Oct. 19; Beck, Theodric Romeyn, 1791-1855
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1852 Nov. 8; Wallich, Nathaniel
  - Note on condition of Mr. Kirkbride, 1852 Dec. 4; Birch, G.
  - Letter to Davis, J. D., 1852 Dec. 7; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Pangru, John L., 1853 Jan. 4; Silliman, Benjamin, Jr., 1816-1885
  - Letter to Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869, 1853 Mar. 16; Kane, John K., (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
  - Letter to Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867, 1853 Mar. 22; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to Forbes, David, 1853 Mar. 23; Wilson, George
  - Letter to Layard, Edgar Leopold, 1824-1900, 1853 Jul. 20; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
  - Note on Mr. Gillbanks, 1853 Oct. 7; Partridge, S. T.
  - Letter to Stephenson, R., 1853 Oct. 31; Ogle, Nathaniel
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1853; Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854
  - Letter to Ross, James Clark, 1854 Mar. 19; Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861
  - Letter to Field, Henry William, 1854 Apr. 25; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
  - Letter to Layard, Edgar Leopold, 1824-1900, 1854 Jun. 9; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
  - Letter to Way, Albert, 1805-1874, 1854 Jun. 10; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
    1963-2111ms
  - Letter to Layard, Edgar Leopold, 1824-1900, 1854 Jun. 26; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861s, 1854 Jun. 26; Gould, John
  - Letter to Purdue, John, 1854 Jul. 25; Wheatley, Charles M.
  - Letter to Walker, Isaac R., 1854 Jul. 27; Kirkbride, Thomas Story, 1809-1883
  - Letter to Herschel, C., 1854 Aug. 31; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
  - Letter to Dixon, William Hepworth, 1821-1879, 1854 Oct. 18; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
  - Letter to James, Horace, 1854 Dec. 9; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1855 Feb. 5; Bowerbank, James Scott, 1797-1877
  - Letter to Strachey, Edward, 1855 May 15; Schlagintweit, Adolph, 1829-1857
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1855 Jun. 6; Murchison, Roderick Impey, Sir, 1792-1871
  - Letter to Gibbs, Laura Wolcott, 1855 Jun. 24; Gibbs, George, 1815-1873
    1974-222ms
  - Letter to Ferrier, James Frederick, 1808-1864, 1855 Jun. 25; Dockray, Benjamin
  - Letter to Dale, R. W., 1855 Jun. 30; Bonner, Albers
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1855 Jul. 10; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to Lamé, 1855 Jul. 15; Gautier
  - Letter to Dockray, Benjamin, 1855 Aug. 10; Ferrier, James Frederick, 1808-1864
  - Letter to Sister, 1855 Aug. 20; Stillé, Alfred, 1813-1900
  - Letter to Dawson, Charles, 1855 Nov. 16; Yarrell, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Heaviside, 1856 Jan. 28; Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861
  - Letter to Lefebvre, Dr., 1856 Jan. 30; Lardner, Dionysius, 1793-1859
  - An Act to enable Peter Cooper to found a Scientific Institution in the City of New York, 1856 Mar. 29; New York. State
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1856 Jun. 28; Williams, C. W.
  - Letter to Monsieur le Président, 1856 Oct. 30; Wilhelm, Paul, Duke of Wurttemberg, 1797-1860
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1857 Jan. 7; Letheby, Henry
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1857 Mar. 2; Farr, William
  - Letter to Frazer, J. H., 1857 Mar. 2; Mapes, James J. (James Jay), 1806-1866
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1857 Apr. 15; Playfair, Lyon Playfair, Baron, 1818-1898
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1857 Jul. 7; American Association for the Advancement of Science.
  - Letter to Sheldly(?), 1857 Aug. 3; Napier, Robert, 1791-1876
    On the back of the letter is a sketch of the point of Gourock-on-Clyde, Aug. 4, 11:50 A.M.
  - Letter to Rogers, W. F., 1857 Sep. 16; Cassin, John, 1813-1869
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1857 Sep. 18; Spence, William
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1857 Sep. 19; Reeve, Lovell, 1814-1865
  - Letter to Caws (?), 1857 Oct. 28; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1857 Dec. 20; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865
  - Letter to Milne-Edwards, H. (Henri), 1800-1885, 1857; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1858 Mar. 21; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Humble, Miss, 1858 Apr. 16; Lassell, William, 1799-1880
  - Letter to Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896, 1858 Apr. 22; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
  - Letter to Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885, 1858 May 27; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
  - Letter to Murray, John, 1808-1892, 1858 Jun. 23; Somerville, Mary, 1780-1872
  - Letter to Suckley, George, 1858 Jun. 25; Richardson, John
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1858 Jul. 2; Tennant, James
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1858 Jul. 14; Clark, James
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1858 Jul. 29; Schlagintweit, Adolph, 1829-1857
  - Letter to Ross, Thomas B., 1858 Oct. 12; Brista, H. G.